The true story of a day that started like any other
22 July is a crime, drama, history film directed by Paul Greengrass.
On 22 July 2011, neo-Nazi terrorist Anders Behring Breivik murdered 77 young people
attending a Labour Party Youth Camp on Utøya Island outside of Oslo.
This three-part story focuses on the survivors, the political
leadership of Norway, and the lawyers involved.
Viljar Hanssen, played by Jonas Strand Gravli.
Anders Behring Breivik, played by Anders Danielsen Lie.
Geir Lippestad, played by Jon Øigarden.
Lara Rashid, played by Seda Witt.
Prime Minister Stoltenberg, played by Ola G. Furuseth.
Christin Kristoffersen, played by Maria Bock.
22 July is a 2018 English-language Norwegian-British crime drama film about the 2011 Norway attacks and their aftermath,
based on the book One of Us: The Story of a Massacre in Norway — and Its Aftermath by Åsne Seierstad.
The film was written, directed and produced by British filmmaker Paul
Greengrass and features a Norwegian cast and crew.
It stars Anders Danielsen Lie, Jon Øigarden,
Thorbjørn Harr, Jonas Strand Gravli, Ola G.
Furuseth, Ulrikke Hansen Døvigen, Isak Bakli Aglen, Maria Bock, and Seda Witt.
The film had its world premiere on September 5, 2018, in the main
competition section of the 75th Venice International Film Festival.
and was released online and in select theaters on  October 10, 2018, by Netflix.
The film explores themes of neo-nazism, summer camp, bomb, aftermath, car bomb.
The tone is emotional and intense.